Guide to the Thomas Alexander McNamara papers, 1881-1933
McNamara, Thomas Alexander papers, 1881-1933
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Thomas Alexander McNamara papers, 1881-1933.
3918
Thomas Alexander McNamara, 1856-1927.
1 cubic ft.
Medical files and ledgers, diplomas and certificates, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes medical files and ledgers, diplomas and certificates, Corning Common Council materials, and various other papers of Thomas A. McNamara, a physician and a mayor of Corning, New York.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Thomas A. McNamara was a physician and a mayor of Corning, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes medical files and ledgers, diplomas and certificates, Corning Common Council materials, and various other papers of Thomas A. McNamara.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McNamara, Thomas Alexander, 1856-1927.; Corning (N.Y.). Common Council.
Subjects:
Physicians--New York (State)--Corning.
Places:
Corning (N.Y.)--Officials and employees.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Autobiography (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Two poems, 1913, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Steuben County Draft Board, 1917, 1919, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Family Automobile Trips, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Whither are we drifting?", 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Eugenics, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- History of Medicine, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mortality in Childbirth, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Rambles in the Obstetric Field", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Science of Medicine (or Medical Culture), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Student Nursing Lectures (?), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Why I am a Catholic, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Estate of Thomas A. McNamara, MD, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
- Medical Office Ledger, 1911-1916 (Box 3)
- Medical Office Ledger, 1917-1920 (Box 3)
- Medical Office Ledger, 1923-1927 (Box 3)
- Real Estate Ledger, 1901-1912 (Box 4)
- Corning Common Council Procedures (Box 4)
- Scrapbook of newspaper articles including Mayor McNamara and the Common Council; also, articles by McNamara, 1908-1909, 1921-1922 (Box 4)
- The Evening Leader (photocopy), 1916-1922 (Box 4)
- Ledger of expenses, 1916-1922 (Box 4)
- University of New York Medical Diploma, 1882 (Folder 1)
- Certificate for course in microscopy, 1881 (Folder 1)
- Medical Society of Steuben County, 1887 (Folder 1)
- Certificate: Practical Chemical Lab., NYU, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Harvard diploma (of Robert F. McNamara), 1932 (Folder 1)
- Harvard diploma (of Robert F. McNamara), 1933 (Folder 1)